# Rodrigo Abbás

E: rodrigoabbas@gmail.com Tucumán, Argentina

# **Professional Summary**

Enthusiastic and highly skilled full stack software developer with +5 years on software industry, +4 years developing web applications, always providing excellent quality results and maintaining skills up-to-date. Strongly committed to team environment dynamics, with excellent problem-solving and debugging skills and a great willingness to learn.

## Work Experience

## SmartFlow - Full Stack Software Engineer Dublin, Ireland 03/2019 - Present

- Developing and maintaining several internal web and desktop applications for IoT devices managing, debugging and system administration with JavaScript (Vue and Node), C# and Python.
- Providing full support for server-side functionalities, developing features and services, maintaining website and databases.
- Performing tests on devices and software applications.
- Designing and coordinating action plans for continuous improvements.

# Safigen - Full Stack Software Developer San Francisco, CA 02/2018 - 10/2018

- Designed and developed responsive Vue JS front-end to show real-time IoT data with different useful features.
- Developed several Node JS microservices to handle and process all incoming data and to support each feature.
- Designed and implemented SQL/NoSQL databases.
- Trained the new team members and staff.

# Sovos - Full Stack Software Developer Tucumán, Argentina 12/2016 - 02/2018

- Designed and built a React-Redux frontend for web application that processes and graphically shows reports for data analysis. Developed several modules and a restful API for its Backend with Node JS.
- Maintained and added several features to an existing web application, working with HTML, CSS and PHP. Simultaneously, migrated its front-end to a React-Redux architecture.
- Provided training for new/other teams members.

# Fcia. Santo Domingo - Software Developer Tucumán, Argentina 06/2016 - 12/2016

 Designed and developed management application for branches, to keep track of sales, suppliers, inventory and additional information, with Node JS, HTML, Bootstrap and MySQL.

**C:** +5493816164583 rodrigoabb.github.io/bio

#### Skills

#### **Frontend**

- JavaScript
- Vue 1S
- HTML
- React JS
- CSS
- Redux
- Bootstrap
- jQuery

#### **Backend**

- Node JS
- Java
- SQL / NoSQL
- C#
- API Design
- PHP

## Frameworks / Utilities

- GIT
- CI/CD tools
- Mocha / Chai
- Jasmine / Jest

## Others

- Software Design
  Web Development
- Database Design
  Agile Methodologies

# **Projects**

# **mOsc** - Tucumán, Argentina 08/2016 - 04/2017

- · Designed and built an oscilloscope for Mobile Devices, using CIAA platform.
- Implemented Android UI, multiple functionalities and integration.
- Created workflow system and communication protocol.

# Post & Fun - Tucumán, Argentina 04/2015 - 10/2015

• Built a simple social network with HTML, JavaScript, CSS, PHP and MySQL

#### Education

## Universidad Nacional De Tucumán

- Tucumán, Argentina

### **Bachelor of Engineering:**

Computer Engineering

• Graduated on 06/2017

## Languages

• Spanish: Native

• English: Fluent